[Road to Success]
[찬여번성: 별처럼 빛나리]
[Episode 23]
[제23화]
You all remember
다들 기억하고 있지?
Robert's Rules of Order
내가 전에 알려 준
I taught you before, right?
로버트 의사 규칙 말이야
Yes.
기억하죠
You make it sound so mysterious,
말은 그럴싸해도
but isn't it just the principle of majority rule?
결국 다수결이잖아요
It seems Qin Ao
보아하니 친아오 학생은
listens very carefully in class.
평소에 수업을 열심히 들었나 보네
This time, we are not going with majority rule.
이번에는 다수결이 아니야
Today,
오늘은
we are going to take a vote.
다 같이 투표를 할 거야
A vote?
투표요?
How?
어떻게요?
Regarding the next match,
다음 시합에 대해서
you haven't reached a conclusion.
계속 기권할지 말지
Should we forfeit?
결론을 못 내리고 있잖아
Forfeit?
기권이요?
If Wen Chengye isn't here,
원청예가 없어도
are we still playing?
경기를 계속할 거야?
Doesn't that mean we aren't playing?
그럼 경기를 안 한다는 거네요
I will give each of you
이따가 너희한테
a blank piece of paper later.
백지를 한 장씩 나눠줄 거야
Those who don't want to play
경기를 하고 싶지 않은 학생은
can draw a cross on it.
종이에 'X' 표시를 하면 돼
If there is even a single cross
열 표 중에서
among the 10 votes,
단 한 표라도 'X'가 나오면
we will...
우리는
forfeit.
기권할 거야
Time's up.
10분 다 됐어
Let's start.
시작하자
Then I'll begin.
그럼 시작할게
The 1st one.
첫 번째 표
Blank.
백지
The last two votes.
마지막 두 장 남았어
I'm having a heart attack.
심장 마비 오겠네
The last one.
마지막 한 장이야
It's the last one.
마지막 한 장 남았다
Blank.
백지
Oh, no.
어떡하지?
I kind of want to cry.
나 진짜 울고 싶어
Why?
울긴 왜 울어?
We won't forfeit.
우린 기권 안 해
Let's beat the crap out of them.
아주 박살을 내주자고
Yeah.
그래
So what if we only have ten people?
열 명이면 뭐 어때?
We're going to play!
무조건 싸워야지
Yeah!
싸우자
-Yeah! -That's right!
- 싸우자 - 나가서 싸우자
-Beat the crap out of them! -We'll play!
- 아주 부숴 버리자 - 그래
-Yeah! -No one says 10 people can't play.
- 싸우자 - 10명으로 안 될 거 있어?
As long as we're together,
우리가 함께라면
we can play even with 10 people!
10명이라도 할 수 있어
It seems the answer is already obvious.
답은 이미 나온 것 같다
Not only will we not give up,
저희는 포기도 없고
but we also can't chicken out!
쫄지도 않을 거예요
With such an ace coach,
에이스 코치님이 계시니까
even with only 10 people,
열 명이 뛴다고 해도
we can still win!
얼마든지 이길 수 있어요
-Right? -Yeah.
- 그렇지? - 맞아
Coach is here.
코치님이 계시잖아
You're too optimistic, Qin Ao.
너무 낙관적이다, 친아오
It's okay even if we lose.
괜찮아요, 져도 상관없어요
We play for fun.
축구는 즐기려고 하는 거잖아요
Right!
맞아
We'll be happy even if we lose?
져도 즐겁긴
If we lose, I'll kick your ass nonstop.
지면 내가 쫓아가서 찰 거야
Can you even catch me?
나 잡을 수 있겠어?
We'll play until we retire!
죽을 때까지 싸운다
That's great.
정말 좋다
I am proud of you.
너희가 자랑스럽다
[Chen Jianghe, Second Class] [Lin Lu, Second Class]
[천장허 2등석] [린루 2등석]
[Hongjing to Chuncheng North Station, D07016]
[훙징에서 북춘청으로 가는 D07016편]
I've booked the tickets.
표는 다 예매했어요
Warm water.
미지근한 물이에요
Thank you.
고마워요
What's wrong?
왜 그래요?
I still don't want to give up on Wen Chengye.
난 아직 원청예를 포기하고 싶지 않아요
Wen Chengye right now
원청예는 지금
is like an injured pufferfish.
상처 입은 복어 같아요
Instead of approaching him,
가까이 다가가는 것보다
it's better
더 좋은 방법은
to let him choose for himself.
스스로 선택하게 하는 거죠
[Hello, Wen Chengye]
[안녕, 원청예]
Pung!
펑
I was so close.
나 거의 다 됐는데
What kind of luck is that?
운이 왜 이렇게 좋아?
I'm on fire!
완전 대박이네
It's all Wang's fault. He keeps dealing into your hands.
다 왕 형 때문이지
I won't give up today.
진짜 못 믿겠네
[Hengjiu Crushed Hongjing No. 8 High]
[훙징 제8고를 대승으로 꺾은 융촨 헝주]
[The Opponent Lost Their Composure]
[상대의 멘탈은 붕괴됐다]
[Yongchuan Hengjiu's Legendary Storyline— More Thrilling Than a Novel]
[융촨 헝주는 판타지 소설보다 더 짜릿한 감동이 있다]
[The Opponent Lost Their Composure]
[상대의 멘탈은 붕괴됐다]
[Yongchuan Hengjiu's Legendary Storyline— More Thrilling Than a Novel]
[융촨 헝주는 판타지 소설보다 더 짜릿한 감동이 있다]
[Inbox]
[수신함]
Hello, Wen Chengye.
안녕, 원청예
[Hongjing No. 8 High School Football Team's Fixtures and Related Assignments]
[훙징 제8고 축구팀 경기 일정 및 관련 숙제]
First, according to the organizing committee,
첫째 조직 위원회 공지에 따라
our next Youth Super League match
유소년 슈퍼 리그 최신 경기 일정이
is scheduled for next Sunday at 2 p.m.
다음 주 일요일 오후 2시로 정해졌어
We will play an away game against Chuncheng Xinpeng.
우리 팀은 춘청 신펑 팀과 원정 경기를 치를 예정이야
The match venue and address are as follows.
자세한 경기장 주소와 위치는 아래 그림을 참고해 줘
[Hongjing No. 8 High School Football Team's Fixtures and Related Assignments]
[훙징 제8고 축구팀 경기 일정 및 관련 숙제]
[Chuncheng North Station] [Yongchuan Chuncheng Sports Center]
[북춘청 역] [융촨성 춘청시 스포츠 센터]
Second, I assigned
둘째 린 선생님이 팀원들한테
homework to the players.
숙제를 내줬어
The topic is:
주제는
Football is for Victory.
'축구는 승리를 위한 것인가'야
You can submit your homework in any format,
숙제 제출 방식은 자유롭게 선택할 수 있어
such as an essay or a comic.
예를 들어 짧은 글이나 만화도 좋아
[Lin Wanxing]
[린완싱]
I hope you'll submit it on time by next Sunday.
다음 주 일요일까지 숙제를 제출해 줘
[Yongchuan Chuncheng Sports Center]
[융촨성 춘청시 스포츠 센터]
Third, I'll send you the match review video
셋째, 경기 복기 영상은
via a cloud drive.
내가 클라우드를 통해 보내 줄게
Please download it yourself.
다운로드 해서 봐
[Lin Wanxing]
[린완싱]
P.S.
PS
We will take the high-speed rail to Chuncheng.
춘청까지는 고속 열차를 타고 갈 건데
The schedule is as follows.
시간과 열차편은 아래에 나와 있어
Swipe your ID card and you'll find a surprise.
신분증을 스캔하면 깜짝 선물이 있을 거야
Your beloved teacher, Lin Wanxing.
너를 진심으로 아끼는 린완싱 선생님이
[Lin Wanxing]
[린완싱]
[Hongjing to Chuncheng North Station, G3001]
[훙징에서 북춘청으로 가는 G3001편]
[Wen Chengye, Second Class] [Fu Xinshu, Second Class]
[원청예 2등석] [푸신수 2등석]
[Qin Ao, Second Class] [Lin Lu, Second Class]
[친아오 2등석] [린루 2등석]
[Chen Jianghe, Second Class] [Zheng Feiyang, Second Class]
[천장허 2등석] [정페이양 2등석]
[Hongjing to Chuncheng North Station, G3001]
[훙징에서 북춘청으로 가는 G3001편]
Weirdo.
황당하네
Now that we are missing Wen Chengye,
지금 원청예가 빠져서
our defense is weak,
우리 수비가 비었으니까
so someone has to drop back from midfield.
미드필더에서 군가 내려와야 해
Actually, I can fill this position.
사실 내가 그 자리를 메울 수 있어
No, you're not tall enough.
안 돼, 넌 키가 작잖아
You're at too much of a disadvantage in aerial duels.
공중볼 다툼에서 밀릴 거야
Then you can do it.
그럼 네가 하면 되잖아
No, how can Chen do it?
장허는 안 되지
If Chen drops back,
장허가 내려가면
I'll be the only one left up front.
우리 공격진에 나 혼자 남잖아
What about our attack?
공격은 어떡하라고?
Yeah, we'd have no forward.
그럼 공격수가 줄어드네
Then can I do it?
내가 내려갈게
I'm pretty good at clearing the ball.
내가 롱킥으로 걷어내는 건 괜찮잖아
Bro, here's the thing.
너는 말이야
You're too soft on defense,
수비가 약해서
so your defending is weak.
그게 네 약점이야
If they get physical with you,
상대가 몸으로 밀고 들어오면
you're done for.
바로 뚫릴 거라고
Right?
맞잖아
Coach,
코치님
we can't reach an agreement.
저희끼리 의견이 안 모아져요
What do you think?
어떻게 생각하세요?
What about you?
너는?
Fu?
푸신수요?
Of course not him.
당연히 안 되죠
He's always been our core in midfield.
계속 우리 팀 미드필더 핵심이었잖아요
Yeah.
맞아
Although he always plays midfield
계속 미드필더를 맡았고
and plays it very well,
미드필더로 서면 실력이 빛을 발하지만
considering our team's current situation,
지금 우리 팀 상황에선
he is the most suitable.
신수가 제일 적합해
We need you
우린 너한테
to bring your passing, long-ball distribution,
중앙 지역에서 짧은 연결이나 롱패스
and game-reading ability
그리고 경기 흐름을 읽는 능력을
to the back line.
수비 지역으로 가져와 줘
Understood.
알겠습니다
But your foot hasn't completely healed, right?
근데 부상이 아직 안 나았잖아
My foot is fine now.
발은 이제 괜찮아
Don't worry about me.
걱정하지 않아도 돼
If there are no other opinions,
그럼 다른 의견 없으면
it's decided.
그렇게 정한다
-Okay. -Let's do it.
- 네 - 그렇게 해요
-I think it's okay. -Okay.
- 그게 낫겠다 - 좋아요
There are only 5 days until the match.
경기까지 5일 남았으니까
You need to get familiar with the new lineup quickly.
다들 빨리 새로운 포메이션에 익숙해지고
Be careful and stay safe.
다치지 않게 조심해
-Okay. -Alright.
- 네
Okay, Ms. Lin.
네, 린 선생님
Thank you, Ms. Lin.
감사합니다, 린 선생님
Let's begin.
그럼 시작하자
Give it a try.
한번 해 보자
-Let's go.
- 가자
Let's start training.
- 연습해 보자
Slow down.
천천히 해
Why the rush?
뭐가 그렇게 급해?
I wasn't me.
내가 건드린 거 아냐
Let's go.
가자
Nice first touch! Pass it to me.
터치 좋다, 패스해
[Four Days Until the Match]
[다음 시합까지 D-4]
♪ Who hasn't known the dark of night and uncertainty? ♪
♪ 누구나 어둠과 방황의 시간을 지나 ♪
♪ Stumbling, covered in wounds, losing direction ♪
♪ 넘어지고 상처투성이가 되며 방향을 잃은 채 ♪
[Four Days Until the Match]
[다음 시합까지 D-4]
♪ Wandering alone, gaining strength through pain ♪
♪ 홀로 헤매지만 그렇게 강해지는 법이야 ♪
[Three Days Until the Match]
[다음 시합까지 D-3]
♪ Riding the wind, chasing an unknown horizon ♪
♪ 바람을 타고 미지의 내일을 향해 달려가 ♪
[Two Days Until the Match]
[다음 시합까지 D-2]
[One Days Until the Match]
[다음 시합까지 D-1]
♪ Looking up, dreaming side by side of great ideals ♪
♪ 고개를 들어 원대한 꿈을 간직한 채 ♪
♪ The vast world awaits youth to arrive ♪
♪ 드넓은 세상에 우린 거침없이 뛰어들 거야 ♪
Do you think we can really win tomorrow?
우리가 내일 이길 수 있을까?
Coach said she never predicts
코치님은 승리 외의 결과는
results other than victory.
예측하지 않으신댔어
Doesn't that mean hope is slim?
그렇게 말하는 건 희망이 없다는 거잖아
I really want to win.
진짜 이기고 싶다
If we lose,
만약 지면
this will be our last game.
이게 우리 마지막 경기잖아
I know you want the best for the team.
네가 누구보다 팀이 잘되길 바라는 거 알아
If you don't want to say it,
말하지 않는 데는
you must have your reasons.
분명 이유가 있겠지
If you have the chance,
기회가 되면
find some time to talk to them.
시간 내서 제대로 얘기 좀 해 봐
Of course we will win.
우리가 당연히 이기지
That's right.
맞아
We definitely will.
우린 무조건 할 수 있어
I'm leaving first.
나 먼저 갈게
I'll get going.
나 먼저 간다
-Okay. -Call me when you get there.
- 그래 - 도착하면 연락해
-Bye-bye!
- 잘 가
This is what I think.
그러니까 내 말은
In our defensive third,
우리가 후방에서
if you get the chance, pass the ball to Fu.
기회가 되면 푸신수한테 패스하고
He'll send a long ball forward.
푸신수가 다시 공을 넘겨주면 된다고
Okay, bye-bye.
- 그래 - 잘 가
I'm telling you,
내 말 좀 들어 봐
the two of you as a...
너희 둘이...
Everyone works so hard.
다들 이렇게 열심히 하는데
-I need to do what I should do as well. -Let's pass the ball to Fu.
- 나도 내 할 일을 해야겠어 - 우리가 공을 신수한테 주고
He'll send a long ball forward.
신수가 롱패스로 넘기면 돼
Then the ball goes to Jianghe.
그럼 장허가 좀 받아서
Jianghe can pass it to Ao.
다시 친아오한테 주면 되고
Got it?
알았지?
That's how it will be.
바로 그거야
I'll just...
내가...
He...
쟤...
Fu, where are you going?
푸신수, 어디 가?
Fu!
푸신수
[Hongjing to Chuncheng North Station, G3001]
[훙징에서 북춘청으로 가는 G3001편]
[Wen Chengye, Second Class]
[원청예 2등석]
[Hongjing to Chuncheng North Station, G3001]
[훙징에서 북춘청으로 가는 G3001편]
I know you resent me for breaking my promise,
내가 약속 어겨서 원망하는 거 알아
and I know you want to know
내가 왜 그랬는지
why I did this.
네가 이유를 알고 싶은 것도 알고
I refused to tell you
내가 말 안 하는 건
because it's...
이 일이
too disgusting.
너무 역겨워서 그래
[Seven years ago]
[7년 전]
A birthday gift for you.
생일 선물이야
-Excuse me. Which ward is Li Xiaomei in? -Hello.
- 리샤오메이 병실이 어디죠? - 안녕하세요
Bed 21. It's in the room down the hall.
21호 침대인데 안쪽 병실에 있어요
Okay, thank you.
네, 감사합니다
Mom, it's my friend's birthday today.
엄마, 오늘 친구 생일이라
I'm going out for a bit.
잠깐 나갔다 올게요
Hello?
여보세요
Is this Guan Minjie?
관민제 씨 맞으십니까?
Yes, this is she.
네, 접니다
I'm a police officer.
저는 파출소 경찰인데요
Your husband got drunk
남편분께서 술에 취해서
and assaulted someone on the street.
길에서 사람을 때려서
The victim is now hospitalized with severe injuries.
피해자가 중상으로 입원했습니다
His family wants to sue him.
피해자 가족이 고소하겠다고 하니까
Please come to the police station immediately
지금 바로 파출소로 오셔서
to cooperate with our investigation.
조사에 협조해 주시기 바랍니다
Okay, I see.
네, 알겠습니다
Mom, what's wrong?
엄마, 무슨 일이에요?
Your dad beat someone up and is in the police station again.
아빠가 또 사람을 때려서 파출소에 갔대
We have to go there.
우리가 가 봐야겠다
What did you just say?
방금 뭐라고 했니?
I have an emergency at home. I have to go.
집에 급한 일이 생겨서 먼저 가 볼게요
Thank you.
고맙습니다
It's fine.
괜찮아요
I'll go get changed first.
옷 갈아입고 올 테니
You're coming with me.
너도 같이 가자
Have you paid the fine?
벌금은 내셨습니까?
[Public Security]
[경찰]
When you get back,
집에 돌아가시면
discipline him properly.
잘 좀 말씀하세요
Here.
여기요
Sign here and you may leave.
여기에 서명하시고 가시면 돼요
Fu Haisheng needs to sign too.
푸하이성 씨도 서명해야 합니다
Fu Haisheng.
푸하이성 씨
Sign here and you may leave.
여기에 서명하면 갈 수 있어요
Thank you.
감사합니다
Goodbye.
안녕히 가세요
Let's go.
가자
I just paid a 5,000 fine.
방금 벌금으로 5천 위안이나 냈어
The salary I just received wasn't enough,
내 월급 받은 걸로는 부족해서
so I borrowed some from my mom.
친정엄마한테 또 빌렸다고
I don't know what to do
이번 달 생활비는
with this month's living expenses.
어떻게 해야 할지 모르겠어
Are you blaming me?
날 원망하는 거야?
No.
아니
Are you?
날 원망하는 거지?
-Don't hit Mom! -Let go of me!
- 엄마를 때리지 마요 - 이거 놔
Blaming me, huh?
날 원망해?
-I'm not! -All you do is blame me!
- 아니야 - 날 원망하잖아
Don't hit Mom!
엄마를 때리지 마요
Get away!
저리 비켜
Look at you!
네 꼴 좀 봐
Just looking at you annoys me!
너만 보면 짜증 나 죽겠어
Stop hitting me!
때리지 마
All you do is blame me!
맨날 나만 원망하고
Blaming me, huh?
날 원망하는 거지?
Blame me one more time and...
더 원망해 봐
-I told you to stop! -Xinshu!
- 엄마를 때리지 말라고 - 신수
How dare you hit Mom!
왜 엄마를 때려?
Stop it!
그만해
Officer.
경찰관님
This little brat was out of line.
이 어린 놈의 새끼가 버릇없게
He actually hit me with a brick.
벽돌로 저를 쳤어요
He even hit me one more time in the face. Look.
제 얼굴을 제대로 날렸다니까요
He almost blinded me.
하마터면 눈이 멀 뻔했어요
You're glaring at me?
또 째려봐 봐
Keep glaring and you'll see!
또 째려보라고
Calm down. Calm down.
진정하시고
Sit.
앉으세요
Officer,
경찰관님
I have a question to ask you.
여쭤볼 게 있는데요
Go ahead.
말씀하세요
Well...
저기...
It's just...
그러니까
Is a violent tendency hereditary?
폭력적인 성향도 유전이 되나요?
Why do you ask?
왜 그걸 물으시는 거죠?
Just now,
아까
when my son hit his dad with a brick,
제 아들이 벽돌로 아빠를 때릴 때
I saw the look in his eyes.
아이의 눈빛을 봤는데
It was exactly the same as his dad's.
자기 아빠랑 똑같았거든요
I'm afraid he
저는 아이가
will be like his dad.
아빠처럼 될까 봐 무섭네요
Well...
그게...
Your son was protecting you.
아드님은 어머니를 지키려고 그런 거잖아요
I know, but I'm afraid of...
알죠, 근데 전 아이가
What if he hits people too
나중에 커서
in the future?
사람을 때릴까 봐 그래요
Like me?
절 때릴 수도 있잖아요
Brat.
녀석아
Did you hear that?
들었냐?
Your mom says you inherited my violent genes.
네가 아비의 폭력성을 물려받았다고 엄마가 그러는데
Are you going to help her?
그래도 엄마 편 들 거야?
Alright.
그만들 하시고
Let's go back first, okay?
일단 돌아가세요
Mom, let's go home.
엄마, 우리 집에 가요
That's the whole story.
일은 그렇게 됐고
That was when I realized,
그때서야 난 깨달았어
I might be just like my dad,
나도 아빠처럼
a kid with violent tendencies.
폭력적인 성향이 있는 아이였을지도 모른다는 걸
Maybe that's the reason my mom
엄마도 아마 그 이유 때문에
abandoned me after the divorce.
이혼하고 날 버렸던 거야
I am really afraid
나도 내가
of turning into someone like my dad.
아빠처럼 될까 봐 두려웠어
Really.
정말로
That's also why
그래서 몇 년 동안
I've been a people pleaser
너희가 계속
in your eyes all these years.
내가 남 비위나 맞추는 사람이라고 생각했겠지
Wen Chengye.
원청예
I want you to play football with us
난 네가 우리랑 같이 축구했으면 좋겠어
because I feel
왜냐하면
I see hope in football.
난 축구를 하면서 희망을 봤거든
I believe you do too.
너도 그럴 거라고 믿어
If... if you can forgive me,
만약 날 용서해 준다면
I am right outside your door.
지금 너희 집 앞이니까 나와
[Fu Xinshu]
[푸신수]
[I am really afraid of turning into someone like my dad.]
[나도 내가 아빠처럼 변할까 봐 두려워]
[That's also why I've been]
[그래서 너희는 내가]
[a people pleaser in your eyes all these years.]
[남 눈치 보는 성격이라고 생각했을 거야]
[If you can forgive me, I am right outside your door.]
[만약 날 용서해 준다면 지금 너희 집 앞이니까 나와]
[Ms. Lin told us to go to Yuanyuan Tutoring Class this weekend.]
[린 선생님이 주말에 위안위안 공부방으로 오래]
[Delete]
[삭제]
[Confirm]
[삭제 확인]
[Ms. Lin told us to go to Yuanyuan Tutoring Class this weekend.]
[린 선생님이 주말에 위안위안 공부방으로 오래]
[Delete]
[삭제]
[Confirm]
[삭제 확인]
[Ms. Lin told us to go to Yuanyuan Tutoring Class this weekend.]
[린 선생님이 주말에 위안위안 공부방으로 오래]
[You can tell me if you run into something like this next time.]
[다음에도 이런 일 있으면 나한테 알려 줘]
[Delete]
[삭제]
[Confirm]
[삭제 확인]
I scheduled a one-on-one
내가 내일 일대일
mock interview tutoring session for you tomorrow.
모의 면접 컨설팅 예약해 뒀다
The materials are on the desk. Read them carefully.
자료는 책상 위에 있으니까 꼼꼼히 살펴봐
Wait.
잠깐
You must go.
넌 무조건 가야 해
I'll go with you.
나도 따라갈 거니까
Morning, Coach!
코치님, 안녕하세요
Morning.
그래
Why aren't your shoes in your bag?
신발은 왜 가방에 안 넣었어?
My bag is full of food.
가방에 먹을 걸 가득 넣었는데
It'd be so dirty to put them together.
신발을 넣으면 더럽잖아요
You're quite neat.
깔끔 떠네
Coach, we're here.
코치님, 저희 왔어요
Morning, Coach.
안녕하세요, 코치님
Morning.
그래
Where's Ms. Lin?
린 선생님은요?
Ms. Lin was afraid you guys would be hungry,
린 선생님은 너희 배고플까 봐
so she went to buy some food.
먹을 거 사러 가셨어
Ms. Lin is so nice.
린 선생님은 정말 좋으신 분이에요
-Coach! -Ms. Lin is the best.
- 코치님 - 역시 린 선생님이셔
Coach!
코치님
Hurry up!
빨리 와
Morning.
안녕
You're here so early?
일찍 왔네
We still have some time.
아직 시간 남았으니까
Let's sit down and take a rest.
일단 앉아서 쉬자
-Okay.
- 네
Let's go.
- 가자
Give me the bag in your left hand. Come on.
왼손 줘 봐
You want to eat food that smells like stinky shoes?
신발 냄새 나는 밥 먹고 싶냐?
A mighty tiger...
허우대만 멀쩡하면 뭐 해?
is savoring the stench of stinky feet.
발냄새가 심한데
Why are you dawdling?
뭘 꾸물거려?
Nothing.
아무것도 아니에요
The teacher I hired for you this time
이번에 내가 부른 분은
is a real admissions officer from a prestigious university.
유명 명문대 입학 사정관이니까
You should cherish this opportunity.
집중해
Whatever.
마음대로 하세요
Going abroad as I said and
얌전히 유학이나 가렴
following the path I've arranged for you is the right thing to do.
내가 정해 준 길을 가는 게 바른길이야
Stop thinking about that low-tier team as soon as possible.
그 삼류 팀 같은 건 그만 포기하고
They are not low-tier.
삼류 아니에요
Then what are they?
삼류 팀이 아니면 뭔데?
Look at the people on the team—
팀에 있는 애들 좀 봐라
complicated family backgrounds
가정환경도 복잡하고
and a father with violent tendencies.
아빠는 폭력 성향까지 있고 말이야
He's so young,
네 친구도 어린 나이에
and he also has violent tendencies.
폭력 성향을 보이더라
What do you mean by that?
그게 무슨 말이에요?
I saw the messages on your phone yesterday.
어제 네 핸드폰에서 메시지를 봤었다
Someone named Fu Xinshu
푸신수라는 애
said he owed you an explanation.
너한테 해명할 게 있다면서
He rambled on and on.
주절주절 길게도 써 놨더구나
How could you look at my phone?
왜 제 핸드폰을 들춰봐요?
And then?
그래서요?
Nothing.
그다음은 없었다
I deleted all the messages
널 현혹하는 그런
that tried to mislead you.
메시지는 다 지웠어
What did he say?
걔가 뭐라고 했는데요?
Stop the car!
차 세워요
[Dangerous stunt. Do not attempt]
[위험한 연출이니 따라하지 마세요]
Come back here!
이리 와
Wen Chengye!
원청예
Come back!
돌아와
[Ticket checking will stop 5 minutes before departure.]
[출발 5분 전에 검표를 마치겠습니다]
They are checking tickets soon. Come back quickly.
곧 표 검사하니까 빨리 와요
Okay, coming.
알았어요, 금방 갈게요
So which one do you usually choose?
그럼 넌 보통 뭐 골라?
I usually go for Keen Hearing or Fitness.
난 보통 청력이나 내구력
I never take Deaf.
자폐는 보통 안 고르지
Ms. Lin said she'll be right here.
린 선생님이 곧 오신대
Let's go in first.
우리 먼저 들어가자
-Okay. -Let's go.
- 네 - 일어나자
-Don't forget your ID cards. -Okay.
- 신분증 잘 챙겨라 - 네
[Warning: Battery depleted. Your phone will shut down in 30 seconds.]
[배터리 잔량 부족으로 30초 후 핸드폰이 꺼집니다]
Qin Ao.
친아오
Qin Ao. Do you have a power bank with you?
너 보조 배터리 가져왔어?
I don't think I have it today.
오늘은 안 가져왔지
Let's deal with it after we get off the train, okay?
이따가 도착하고 얘기하자
[Ticket checking has closed for the train to Chuncheng North Station.]
[훙징에서 북춘청으로 가는 열차 검표를 마치겠습니다]
The train from Hongjing to Chuncheng has departed.
훙징에서 춘청으로 가는 열차가 출발했습니다
The train from Shenguang North Station
북선광에서 서융푸로 가는 열차는
to Yongfu West Station is departing at 9:30.
9시 30분에 곧 출발합니다
[Information Service]
[정보 서비스]
[Automatic Ticketing]
[키오스크 매표소]
Chuncheng!
춘청
[Ticket Vending Machine]
[기차 티켓 무인 발권기]
[Departure: Hongjing] [Destination: Chuncheng North Station]
[출발지 훙징] [목적지 북춘청]
Please select your arrival station on the left.
왼쪽에서 도착역을 선택해 주십시오
Please select the departure date.
탑승 날짜를
[Departure Date]
[열차 일정]
[No Matching Trains Found]
[조회된 열차가 없습니다]
[Ticket Vending Machine]
[기차 티켓 무인 발권기]
Hey, young man.
저기요
Are you going to Chuncheng?
춘청 가시는 거예요?
If high-speed rail tickets are sold out,
고속철도 표가 없으면
you can check the long-distance bus station next door.
옆에 있는 시외버스 터미널에 한번 가 보세요
Over there?
어느 쪽이죠?
Right next door.
바로 옆에 있어요
Thank you.
감사합니다
You're welcome.
아닙니다
[Automatic Ticketing]
[키오스크 매표소]
We've already departed.
우리 출발했어
Even though you didn't come,
네가 오진 않았지만
I still want to tell you
그래도 말해 주고 싶어
that I really want you to play with us.
너랑 같이 축구하고 싶다고
We will try hard to win.
우리가 열심히 해서 이길게
If you don't come this time,
이번에 네가 안 오면
we'll try to have a next time.
우린 다음 기회를 노릴 거야
I'm on my way to Chuncheng.
지금 춘청에 가는 길이야
I won't wait for the next time.
다음은 없어
I'm coming this time.
이번에 꼭 갈 거야
We must win.
우리 꼭 이겨야 해
Where are you?
너 어디야?
For this stupid match,
그깟 시합 때문에
are you giving up your future?
네 앞길을 포기하겠다고?
I am giving you a choice now.
지금 선택해
Either you get your ass back here now,
당장 돌아오든가
or you never come back to this house!
아니면 평생 이 집에 돌아올 생각 말든가
It's almost time to go.
슬슬 나가자
The goal for today's match
오늘 경기 목표는
is to lose by as little as possible.
최소 실점으로 지는 거다
On the field, regardless of your position,
각자 경기장에서 어떤 포지션을 맡든
you must always remember to be ready to defend.
항상 수비 복귀할 준비를 해야 한다는 걸 명심해
Got it, Coach.
알겠습니다, 코치님
We will try our best to hold them off.
최선을 다해 막아낼게요
Let me ask you a question.
하나만 물어보자
Among the upcoming attacks
앞으로
we might face,
우리가 마주할 공격 중에서
which one do you most want to stop?
어떤 슈팅을 제일 먼저 막고 싶어?
Sorry, Coach.
죄송하지만
We don't know.
그건 잘 모르겠어요
Think with your heart
마음으로 생각하고
and feel it on the field.
경기장에 가서 직접 느껴 봐
Let's go.
나가자
-Go for it. -Okay! Let's go!
- 파이팅 - 가자
Here is the match between Hongjing No. 8 High School
여기는 훙징 제8고등학교와
and Chuncheng Xinpeng.
춘청 신펑의 경기 현장입니다
The game is about to begin.
경기가 곧 시작되겠습니다
We have just received news
방금 들어온 소식입니다
[Yongchuan Provincial Youth Super League]
[융촨 유소년 슈퍼 리그]
that for this match,
이번 경기에서
[Hongjing No. 8 High School vs. Chuncheng Xinpeng]
[훙징 제8고 vs 춘청 신펑]
due to various reasons, Hongjing No. 8 High School
훙징 제8고의 여러 사정으로 인해
will only have 10 players available.
10명만 출전하게 됐는데요
Their courage is truly admirable.
그 용기가 정말 대단합니다
[Hongjing No. 8 High 0-0 Chuncheng Xinpeng]
[홍징 제8고 00] [춘청 신펑 00]
However, in their previous match against Hengjiu,
하지만 지난 헝주와의 경기에서
Hongjing No. 8 High School suffered a heavy 11-0 defeat.
훙징 제8고는 0 대 11로 참패를 당했는데
With one player down this time, can they
이번에 한 명이 부족한 상황에서
really turn things around
과연 이 부진을 딛고
and claim victory?
승리할 수 있을까요?
Let's wait and see.
함께 지켜보시죠
-We've got this!
- 파이팅
The match has now officially started,
이제 경기 시작합니다
with Hongjing No. 8 High School kicking off.
훙징 제8고의 선축으로 시작하겠습니다
-We can see that Hongjing No. 8 High School -Here!
- 훙징 제8고가 - 여기
has started the game on the front foot.
이번 경기 초반부터 아주 적극적으로 움직입니다
The players are trying to control the tempo
선수들이 적극적인 몸싸움으로
through aggressive pressing and challenges.
흐름을 잡으려 하고 있네요
It is a good idea,
좋은 생각입니다
but reality is harsh.
하지만 현실은 냉혹하죠
After all, they are playing with one player short.
어쨌든 한 명이 부족한 상황이니까요
-As expected, Xinpeng have taken control of the game -I'll cover!
- 역시 신펑이 경기를 지배해 - 내가 마크할게
and are piling on the pressure!
맹공을 퍼붓고 있습니다
Lin Lu wins the ball back.
린루 선수가 공을 가로챕니다
Xinpeng's No. 7 picks it up on the wing,
신펑의 7번 선수가 사이드에서 공을 잡고
beats the midfielder,
미드필더를 제친 뒤
gets past the defender,
수비수까지 따돌리고
and drives into the box!
페널티 구역으로 빠르게 파고듭니다
[Hongjing to Chuncheng]
[훙징에서 춘청 가는 버스]
There's a fire over there.
불이 났나?
Looks pretty bad.
상황이 좀 심각한 것 같아요
It'll probably take a while for the traffic police to clear it.
교통경찰이 처리하려면 한참 걸리겠는데요?
It's a national highway, not an expressway.
국도는 고속도로랑 달라서
If traffic backs up, it'll be at least an hour.
한번 막히면 기본 한 시간이에요
[2:14 PM]
[오후 2시 14분]
Wen Chengye,
원청예
it's okay that you're missing this match.
이번 경기에 참가를 못 해도 괜찮아
There'll be other opportunities.
우리한테 다음이 있잖아
I just want you to see
그냥 네가 팀원들이
how your teammates fight
경기장에서 얼마나
and never give up on the field.
열심히 싸우고 버티는지 봤으면 좋겠다
[Ms. Lin]
[선생님]
[Wen Chengye]
[원청예]
Ms. Lin, I'm on my way.
선생님, 지금 가고 있는데
There's been a little situation.
사고 수습하고 있어서
Wait for me.
좀만 기다려 주세요
Wen Chengye said he's on his way.
원청예가 지금 오고 있대요
Don't worry.
걱정 마요
They can hold out until Wen Chengye arrives.
애들은 원청예가 올 때까지 버틸 수 있어요
[Wen Chengye]
[원청예]
Be careful on the way.
조심히 와
We are all waiting for you.
우리가 기다리고 있을게
Hongjing No. 8 High School have fallen back into a defensive shape.
훙징 제8고의 진영은 완전히 수비로 전환됩니다
Every player is in their own half.
선수들 모두 자기 진영으로 돌아가도
The disadvantage of playing with one man down is very obvious.
선수 한 명이 부족한 약점을 극복하지 못한 것 같습니다
Come on, Zhi Hui, the middle!
즈후이, 중앙 막아
Xinpeng are now almost completely
신펑팀이
in control of the game.
경기장의 흐름을 완전히 장악했습니다
But Hongjing haven't given up.
하지만 훙징도 포기하지 않고
They're still pressing aggressively.
여전히 적극적으로 볼을 다투고 있습니다
Hopefully their stamina
선수들의 체력이
can last until the end.
끝까지 버텨 주길 바랍니다
Xinpeng are passing the ball around,
지금 신펑의 패스를 보시죠
looking to break through the middle.
중앙으로 침투하려는 시도입니다
Hongjing's No. 9, Qin Ao,
훙징의 9번 친아오 선수
makes a brilliant sliding tackle
멋진 슬라이딩 태클로
to clear the ball
공을 걷어내며
and stop a dangerous attack.
위협적인 공격이 될 뻔한 상황을 막아냈습니다
The middle, Zhi Hui!
중앙을 봐, 즈후이
Cover!
커버해, 커버
Over there!
저쪽이야
Come on! Cover the right!
오른쪽으로 한 명 붙어
Come on!
파이팅
Xinpeng win back possession once again.
신펑이 다시 공을 점유하며
Qin Ao is tracking back.
친아오가 뒤쫓고 있습니다
Hongjing make another successful interception.
훙징이 또 한 번 성공적으로 가로챕니다
Again!
다시 해
Even if I can't score,
내가 골은 못 넣어도
I won't let your defenders get past midfield.
네 수비수가 하프라인은 못 넘게 할 거야
No.
안 되겠다
I have to tell Ms. Lin.
린 선생님께 말씀드려야겠어
Oh no, Wen Chengye is stuck in traffic.
어떡해요? 원청예가 길에서 막혔나 봐요
Don't worry, there's still time.
걱정 마요 아직 시간 많아요
Xinpeng are making good use of their numerical advantage,
신펑팀이 수적 우세를 이용해
patiently moving the ball around to stretch Hongjing's defense.
차분하게 훙징의 수비 라인을 흔들고 있습니다
Xinpeng keep building the attack.
신펑팀이 계속해서 공격을 시도하는데
The ball reaches Xinpeng's No. 10.
공이 신펑 10번 선수에게 갔습니다
A Hongjing No. 8 High player closes him down,
훙징 제8고 선수들이 앞으로 나와 압박하며
trying to cut off his passing options.
패스 길을 차단하려 합니다
No. 10 plays it out wide!
10번 선수가 측면으로 공을 보냅니다
Cross into the box!
크로스
The ball is sent into the penalty area,
공이 페널티 지역으로 날아갑니다
but Feng Suo gets a foot to it and knocks it away!
펑쒀 선수가 발로 공을 막아냈습니다
Today,
오늘
Hongjing goalkeeper Feng Suo
훙징의 골키퍼 펑쒀 선수의 활약이
has been outstanding,
매우 눈에 띕니다
making one save after another
계속되는 슈퍼 세이브로
and keeping Hongjing's hopes
훙징이 끝까지 싸울 수 있는
alive.
마지막 희망을 지켜 주고 있습니다
Left!
왼쪽 막아
We're now in the
경기는 어느덧
35th minute of the first half.
전반 35분에 접어들었습니다
The determined Hongjing No. 8 High School
끈질긴 훙징 제8고가
are still holding on,
여전히 자신들의 골문을 지키고 있습니다
with the score level at 0-0.
0 대 0입니다
That's a foul!
파울입니다
A Hongjing player commits a foul with an accidental push.
훙징이 상대를 밀어 파울을 범했습니다
Fortunately, it wasn't serious or intentional.
다행히 동작이 크지 않아 고의성이 없다고 보고
The referee awards a direct free kick
주심이 직접 프리킥을 선언합니다
but keeps the cards in his pocket.
카드는 꺼내지 않았군요
Xinpeng's captain
신펑의 주장이
sends the ball into the box.
골문 앞으로 공을 띄웁니다
No. 11 is trying to get on the end of it!
11번 선수가 쇄도하며
A diving header!
몸을 날려 헤딩합니다
Goal!
골입니다
It's 1-0!
1 대 0
Chuncheng Xinpeng
춘청 신펑이
have broken the deadlock.
경기장의 균형을 깼습니다
Even Feng Suo, who is in great form today,
오늘 신들린 선방을 보여 준 펑쒀 선수라도
had no chance of stopping that one.
이 골은 속수무책일 수밖에 없네요
Captain. Captain.
주장, 주장
1-0.
1 대 0이야
You guys aren't that good.
너희 별거 아니네
Good shot, brothers!
잘했어, 얘들아
Let's keep this up!
이대로만 하자
Keep this up!
모여
-Let's continue! -One more goal!
- 계속 몰아붙여 - 또 넣자
One more!
한 골 더
We are one man down.
한 명이 부족한 우리한테
What is he so arrogant about?
쟤는 왜 이렇게 나대는 거야?
It's fine.
괜찮아
Come on, everyone!
다들 힘내
Keep it up!
파이팅
No problem!
문제없어
It was actually a pass.
패스였다니
What a pity.
너무 아쉽네요
The first half is almost over.
전반전 거의 다 끝났는데
Zhou Siyan knew the risk of shooting directly was high.
저우쓰옌은 직접 슛하는 게 리스크가 크다는 걸 알아요
From that position,
저 위치에서
no matter how much he curled the ball,
아무리 멋진 감아차기라도
it'd most likely be blocked.
막힐 확률이 높거든요
If Wen Chengye had been here...
만약 원청예가 있었다면요?
If he had been there,
청예가 있었다면
all he had to do was track back in time
제때 수비로 복귀하거나
or put a little pressure on the ball in the box,
페널티 구역에서 공을 방해해서
and it wouldn't have gone in.
골이 안 들어갔겠죠
The ball landed right where I was supposed to be defending.
공이 떨어진 지점이 딱 내가 수비하던 위치잖아
Damn it!
젠장
[Think about what you've done!]
[지금 네 선택을 잘 생각하거라]
We could've prevented that goal!
분명히 막을 수 있었는데
[Dad]
[아빠 전화]
Get your ass back here!
[아빠]
Think about what you've done.
지금 네 선택을 잘 생각하거라
[Lin Wanxing]
[린완싱]
Ms. Lin.
린 선생님
Wait for me.
조금만 더 기다려 주세요
I'll be there.
곧 도착해요
Tell them
애들한테 전해 주세요
to hold on.
꼭 버티고
Wait for me.
기다려 달라고요
Sir!
기사님
Sir, open the door.
기사님, 문 열어 주세요
I need to get off!
저 내릴게요
Nineteen.
19개야
We blocked 19 shots.
우리가 슈팅 19개를 막았다고
It was my fault for setting up the defensive line.
내가 수비 라인을 잘못 짠 탓이야
I really didn't expect them to cooperate.
걔들이 협력 플레이를 할 줄은 몰랐어
I was too slow to cover.
내가 커버가 늦었어
No.
아니야
It was my fault for not blocking the shot.
내가 공을 못 막은 거야
It was my fault.
내 문제야
Wen Chengye said he's coming.
원청예가 온다고 했어
Wen Chengye?
원청예가요?
He's coming?
온다고요?
Wen Chengye is coming?
원청예가 온대
[WeChat]
[메신저]
[Wen Chengye]
[원청예]
I'm on my way to Chuncheng.
나 지금 춘청으로 가고 있어
No next time.
다음은 없어
I'm coming this time.
지금 당장 갈 거야
We must win.
우리가 꼭 이겨야 해
Wen Chengye is really coming.
원청예가 진짜 오네
[Youth Football Super League]
[유소년 슈퍼 리그]
He's on his way!
지금 오고 있대
My god.
대박
Is he crazy?
완전 돌았네
It's already this late.
지금 이 시간에
What's the point?
와서 뭐 하게?
Yeah.
그러니까
What's the use of him coming now?
지금 와서 무슨 소용이야?
Because he wants to win.
이기고 싶으니까
I mean,
우리 다
we all want to win,
이기고 싶은 거
don't we?
아니었어?
Right.
맞아
I want to win.
나도 이기고 싶어
Then let's play until we're satisfied.
그럼 후회 없이 모든 걸 쏟아붓자
Let's do it!
그래
Come on, brothers!
얘들아
Let's score two more in the second half.
후반전에 두 골 더 넣자
Wen Chengye,
원청예
you are not the only one who wants to win.
이기고 싶은 건 너뿐만이 아니야
The second half is underway.
후반전 경기가 계속됩니다
No. 6, Lin Lu,
6번 린루 선수
comes in too aggressively.
압박이 너무 거세네요
He charges in from the side at full speed
측면에서 빠르게 달려들면서
but can't stop his momentum
동작을 제어하지 못하고
-and crashes into the opponent, sending him to the ground. -Hongjing's No. 6 commits a foul!
- 상대 선수와 부딪혔습니다 - 훙징 6번 선수 반칙입니다
-A charging foul! -Yellow card warning.
- 반칙입니다 - 옐로 카드입니다
The referee makes the decision quickly and shows Lin Lu a yellow card.
심판이 바로 옐로카드를 꺼내 드네요
Hongjing are really having a tough time now.
훙징은 엎친 데 덮친 격입니다
It's too hard.
정말 힘든 상황인데
If Lin Lu picks up another yellow card,
만약 린루 선수가 옐로카드를 한 장 더 받으면
he'll be sent off,
경고 누적으로 퇴장당하게 되고
leaving Hongjing with only 9 players against 11.
훙징은 9 대 11로 싸워야 합니다
[Microphone is on] [Speaker on] [Camera off]
[스피커폰 켜짐] [카메라 끄기]
Wen Chengye.
원청예
I don't know
시간 맞춰
[Microphone is on] [Speaker on] [Camera off]
[스피커폰 켜짐] [카메라 끄기]
if there's still time.
도착할 수 있을지 모르겠어요
But I'll still come.
그래도 갈 거예요
I definitely will.
반드시
Wait for me.
기다려 주세요
You must wait for me!
꼭 기다려 주세요
We are all waiting for you.
우리 다 기다리고 있어
Hold on!
막아
The players on the field are exhausted.
선수들의 체력 소모가 굉장히 큽니다
Especially for Hongjing No. 8 High School,
특히 한 명이 부족한
who are playing with one man down,
훙징 제8고에게는
the test is even more cruel.
더욱 가혹한 시점이네요
Xinpeng's attack is very swift and fierce.
신펑의 공격이 아주 매섭습니다
-They are relentlessly attacking -Nice ball!
- 훙징 제8고의 수비 라인을 - 좋았어
Hongjing No. 8 High School's defense.
미친 듯이 파고들고 있습니다
Can Hongjing hold on?
훙징이 과연 버틸 수 있을까요?
Goalkeeper Feng Suo
골키퍼 펑쒀 선수
makes another key save!
또 한 번 결정적인 선방을 해냅니다
-He crashed into the pillar. -Let's go!
- 골대와 강하게 부딪혔지만 - 나가
-But he held the ball tightly. -Qin Ao!
- 공을 꽉 끌어안으며 - 친아오
The ball is blocked!
슈팅을 막았습니다
♪ Who hasn't known the dark of night and uncertainty? ♪
♪ 누구나 어둠과 방황의 시간을 지나 ♪
Hongjing finally gets a
훙징이 드디어
rare counterattack opportunity.
귀중한 역습 기회를 잡았습니다
No. 9 Qin Ao breaks through one-on-one,
9번 친아오 선수가 단독 돌파 시도합니다
♪ Stumbling, covered in wounds, losing direction ♪
♪ 넘어지고 상처투성이가 되며 방향을 잃은 채 ♪
charging forward with everything he has!
그대로 돌진하는군요
♪ Wandering alone, gaining strength through pain ♪
♪ 홀로 헤매지만 그렇게 강해지는 법이야 ♪
♪ Riding the wind, chasing an unknown horizon ♪
♪ 바람을 타고 미지의 내일을 향해 달려가 ♪
♪ Looking up, dreaming side by side of great ideals ♪
♪ 고개를 들어 원대한 꿈을 간직한 채 ♪
♪ The vast world awaits youth to arrive ♪
♪ 드넓은 세상에 우린 거침없이 뛰어들 거야 ♪
♪ If braving the wind and waves ♪
♪ 거센 풍파를 용감하게 마주하는 것만이 ♪
♪ What it takes to grow ♪
♪ 성장이라고 한다면 ♪
♪ I will stubbornly go against the current ♪
♪ 난 기꺼이 그곳에서 ♪
♪ And let myself go wild ♪
♪ 뜨겁게 싸워 볼 거야 ♪
♪ No matter how long the road ahead ♪
♪ 미래가 멀다 해도 ♪
♪ Nothing can stop me ♪
♪ 내 질주는 멈추지 않아 ♪
♪ Break through every haze of doubt ♪
♪ 모든 방황을 부수며 ♪
The match has reached the 87th minute.
경기는 후반 87분을 향해 가고 있습니다
♪ Chase the light within me ♪
♪ 나만의 빛을 쫓아가 ♪
Hongjing No. 8 High School are still trailing 0-1,
훙징 제8고는 여전히 0 대 1로 뒤지고 있지만
♪ Strong wings grow through the storm ♪
♪ 풍파 속에서 끝내 강인한 날개를 펼칠 테니까 ♪
but the players have never given up.
선수들은 포기하지 않고 있습니다
♪ Even if no one cheers ♪
♪ 모두가 날 외면해도 ♪
-The Hongjing goalkeeper has once again -Suo!
- 훙징의 골키퍼는 수차례 - 펑쒀
pulled off several incredible saves
감동적인 수비와
and heroic defensive efforts!
선방을 보여 줬습니다
♪ I'll keep fighting my way through ♪
♪ 힘을 다해 싸울 거야 ♪
Let's remember his name:
저 선수의 이름을 기억해야겠습니다
Feng Suo!
저 선수는 펑쒀입니다
As long as I don't give up on scoring,
끝까지 골을 포기하지 않는 한
♪ On a deserted battlefield ♪
♪ 아무도 없는 경기장에서 ♪
I can hold back the opponent's defender.
내가 상대 수비수를 묶어둘 수 있어
♪ Thrive and bloom ♪
♪ 당당하게 성장해 ♪
I can't give up attacking!
공격을 포기하지 않을 거야
I absolutely cannot give up!
절대 포기 안 해
♪ I'll take every scar ♪
♪ 모든 상처를 ♪
♪ As my badge of honor ♪
♪ 영광의 훈장으로 삼을 거야 ♪
♪ If braving the wind and waves ♪
♪ 거센 풍파를 용감하게 마주하는 것만이 ♪
♪ What it takes to grow ♪
♪ 성장이라고 한다면 ♪
♪ I will stubbornly go against the current ♪
♪ 난 기꺼이 그곳에서 ♪
♪ And let myself go wild ♪
♪ 뜨겁게 싸워 볼 거야 ♪
♪ No matter how long the road ahead ♪
♪ 미래가 멀다 해도 ♪
♪ Nothing can stop me ♪
♪ 내 질주는 멈추지 않아 ♪
♪ Break through every haze of doubt ♪
♪ 모든 방황을 부수며 ♪
♪ Chase the light within me ♪
♪ 나만의 빛을 쫓아가 ♪
♪ Strong wings grow through the storm ♪
♪ 풍파 속에서 끝내 강인한 날개를 펼칠 테니까 ♪
♪ Even if no one cheers ♪
♪ 모두가 날 외면해도 ♪
♪ I'll keep fighting my way through ♪
♪ 힘을 다해 싸울 거야 ♪
Nice ball!
좋았어
♪ On a deserted battlefield ♪
♪ 아무도 없는 경기장에서 ♪
The 22nd.
22개째다
♪ Thrive and bloom ♪
♪ 당당하게 성장해 ♪
♪ I'll take every scar ♪
♪ 모든 상처를 ♪
♪ As my badge of honor ♪
♪ 영광의 훈장으로 삼을 거야 ♪
The 23rd.
23개째야
Xinpeng, unable to score for a long time,
신펑이 계속 공격하며
start to launch their fiercest attack.
맹렬하게 골문을 두드리고 있습니다
Playing with 10 men
훙징은 10명으로 맞서고 있어서
is a huge drain on Hongjing's stamina.
체력 소모가 만만치 않겠지만
Hold on!
버텨야 합니다
I'll save this shot even if it kills me!
이 공은 죽어도 막는다
It's the last shot.
마지막 공이야
The match is over.
경기 종료됩니다
The final score is 0-1.
스코어는 0 대 1입니다
Thanks to both sides for bringing us a wonderful match,
멋진 경기를 보여 준 양 팀 선수들에게 감사드립니다
a magnificent 10-against-11 performance.
10 대 11의 정말 멋진 승부였습니다
Hongjing go down with honor.
훙징은 졌지만 잘 싸웠습니다
They have won everyone's respect.
모두의 존경을 받기에 충분했습니다
With running, sweat, and even their bodies,
그들의 질주와 땀 그리고 온몸으로
they defended not only the goal
골문뿐만 아니라
but also their belief and dignity.
신념과 존엄까지 지켜냈습니다
We were so close!
조금만 더 하면 되는데
Coach asked us which attack we wanted to stop.
코치님이 어떤 슈팅을 막고 싶냐고 물으셨잖아
I know the answer now.
이제야 알겠어
This one,
이번 슈팅
the next one,
다음 슈팅
and every one.
모든 슈팅
No matter which attack,
그 어떤 슈팅이든
we have to stop it.
우린 다 막아내야 하는 거야
Wen Chengye?
원청예
Wen Chengye is here.
원청예가 왔어요
I'm sorry.
미안해
I'm the one who should say sorry.
내가 오히려 미안하지
I'm sorry, everyone.
너희한테 정말 미안해
I'm sorry.
미안해
I'm truly sorry.
정말로 미안해
You once asked me
예전에 나한테
what football is.
축구가 뭐냐고 물었었죠?
I have thought about this question
그 질문에 대해
for a very long time,
정말 오랫동안 생각했었어요
because I felt it was too hard.
답하기 너무 어려웠거든요
But now,
하지만 이제는
I seem to finally have an answer.
드디어 답을 찾은 것 같아요
Football is competition
축구는 경쟁이고
and confrontation.
대항이며
It is the desire to still stand on the pitch
수없이 다툰 뒤에도
with your teammates after countless disagreements.
팀원들과 함께 경기장에 서고 싶은 충동이에요
♪ Time's passing by ♪
♪ 세월은 물처럼 ♪
♪ Nothing remains ♪
♪ 흔적도 없이 흘러가고 ♪
It is wanting to give up
포기하고 싶어도
♪ All the dreamers awake alone ♪
♪ 함께 꿈꾸던 우리 쉽사리 잠들지 못하네 ♪
but being unable to,
포기할 수 없어서
and finding the courage to keep moving forward.
굳건히 나아가게 하는 용기고
♪ Shadows above ♪
♪ 때로는 먹구름이 드리우고 ♪
It is refusing
달갑지 않아도
♪ Rain falls around ♪
♪ 축축한 빗물이 삶의 구석구석을 적셔도 ♪
to surrender to fate.
운명을 인정하지 않는 거예요
♪ In your arms ♪
♪ 네 품 안에서 ♪
♪ We become one ♪
♪ 평행하던 우리 세상은 마침내 하나가 돼 ♪
♪ Through day and night ♪
♪ 낮과 밤이 흘러도 ♪
♪ I can see you ♪
♪ 너의 눈동자 속에서 ♪
♪ In my eyes ♪
♪ 진짜 나를 마주해 ♪
♪ Just hold me tight ♪
♪ 꼭 안아 주기만 하면 ♪
♪ Look into my soul so deeply ♪
♪ 너의 시선은 내 영혼 깊숙이 닿아 ♪
♪ Rainbow sunlight ♪
♪ 무지갯빛 후광 아래 ♪
♪ Painful tears are gone ♪
♪ 아픈 지난날은 어제가 되고 ♪
♪ Wonderful days ♪
♪ 반짝이는 아름다운 꿈은 ♪